## Summary

Jay Fallon is a User Experience professional with years of experience in product design and development for a list of clients that includes large enterprises, small businesses and start-up ventures. Jay's interests lie in customer focused application design and development, rapid and iterative prototyping, user-centric design and testing methodologies, the responsive experience and courseware design and development.

## Experience

#### SENIOR UI/UX DEVELOPER; SYRINX CONSULTING - BOSTON, MA

June 2018 - Present

As a contracted UI/UX developer at Bose Corporation, Jay is responsible for providing technical direction, training and support for a fifty-person research department focused on enhancing Bose's future capabilities in personalized customer experience. In this role, Jay provides not only daily deliverable work but also works across teams and disciplines to design, test and provide tangible results for further iterations via web applications, landing pages and emails.

#### UX DESIGNER AND DEVELOPER; JAMES FALLON CONSULTING - BOSTON, MA

September 2009 - December 2010, June 2016 - June 2018

Responsible for assisting clients with web-based strategies, product research, design and development. Project engagements include working with Style Me Pretty on their upcoming website release, a ground-up overhaul of their existing products. Jay's responsibilities included working closely with the client to craft and implement a comprehensive experience strategy in addition to providing research, design and demonstration deliverables.

#### **UX DESIGNER AND DEVELOPER; CENGAGE LEARNING - BOSTON, MA**

March 2014 - June 2016

In addition to creating an in-house CSS framework and reusable component library, Jay was also tasked with providing design and development on multiple Cengage projects that included legacy code conversion, cross-platform CSS standardization, component design and user testing.

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER, UX DESIGNER; BOSTON TECHNOLOGIES, INC. - BOSTON, MA

December 2010 - March 2012

Working in conjunction with a development team, Jay was responsible for the user experience and front-end architecture, design and development on a foreign exchange trading platform. Duties included research, development and testing for both internal and external product offerings in the form of web-based dashboards, trading applications and analysis.

#### UX DEVELOPER; STATE STREET GLOBAL ADVISORS, INC. - BOSTON, MA

June 2007 - September 2008

As a consultant, Jay worked closely with multiple internal teams on projects requiring design, development and ongoing maintenance for existing, new and transitioning web-based products. Jay's re-

sponsibilities included the design, production and deployment of deliverables along with providing testing and technical support.

#### UX DESIGNER AND DEVELOPER; NETNUMINA SOLUTIONS, INC. - CAMBRIDGE, MA

June 2000 - December 2006

Duties include providing technical expertise to account managers, user experience and development teams as well as executing the user experience requirements into deliverables for integration with web applications or standalone websites. Client list includes Fidelity Management & Resource Company, State Street Global Advisors, Johnson & Johnson, Pfizer and ADQSR.

#### Education

# Master of Liberal Arts, degree candidate, Extension Studies, Harvard University, Cambridge MA. January 2017 - Present

Concentration in Digital Design, with work in information systems, courseware design and production, software development. Expected graduation in May 2019.

### Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, Northeastern University, Boston MA.

September 1993 - June 1998

Majored in International Business and Finance. Completed cooperative education assignments at Boston's Better Snacks, FMRC and PictureTel with learning opportunities and responsibilities in operations, marketing, technical documentation and internationalization.

#### Skills

User experience design, interaction design, information architecture, usability testing, front-end development to include modern CSS, HTML, React (React, React Native, Next.js, Gatsby.js), AngularJS, GraphQL, Node/Express, JSX, Jade/Pug, Styled Components, PostCSS, Sass/Scss, LESS, Stylus, Git, responsive design, Python, Ruby/Rails, Java-based frameworks; audio-visual creation and design to include Sketch, InVision, OmniGraffle, Framer, Adobe Premiere, After Effects, Illustrator, Photoshop and Audition. Agile methodologies. Fluent in both English and Spanish.